TYLER GARLICK

(407) 624-2045 | tjgarlick@gmail.com | 1436 N 50 W Centerville, UT 84014

COMMUNICATION AND BUSINESS SKILLS

Strong Leadership: Student Body President at Neumont University and West Orange High School. Awarded the Eagle Scout from BSA when 13 years old. Team leader on various projects and teams. **Strong Verbal Communication:** Planned and strategized with clients on various projects. Documented systems for clients. Fluent in Portuguese.

TECHNICAL COMPETENCIES

Languages: JavaScript, Java, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Node.js, C#

Methodologies: Scrum, Kanban, Test Driven Development, Component Driven Development **Technologies and Frameworks:** N-Tier, REST, WebApi, <u>asp.net</u> MVC/WebApi/WebForms, Express, Mongoose, AngularJS, Twitter Bootstrap, Javascript, CoffeeScript, Rails, Entity Framework, Dapper

Databases: SQL Server 2005 - 2012 R2, Postgres, MongoDB, ArangoDB, RavenDB

Tools: Visual Studio 2008 - 2013, WebStorm, UML, ORM, Azure, PowerShell, Bash, git, tfs, svn, Azure,

Semantic Versioning

Social Profiles

LinkedIn: http://linkedin.com/in/tylergarlick **GitHub:** http://github.com/tylergarlick

NuGet: https://www.nuget.org/profiles/tylergarlick/

EDUCATION

BACHELORS OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE I NEUMONT UNIVERSITY I DEC '08 143 S. Main Street SLC, UT 84111 http://www.neumont.edu

WORK EXPERIENCE

STREAMLINE TECHNOLOGY I ORLANDO, FL

Jan 1999 - July 2000 | July 2006 - Mar. 2007 | Oct 2012 - Feb 2014 Senior Software Architect

Responsibilities

- Enforcing coding standard and practices
- · Building REST components
- · Creating developer frameworks to ease project implementation
- · Work hand-in-hand with developers to maintain coding standards, and build up coding knowledge

Notable Projects

- Security Component Built robust security architecture based on OAuth2, active directory, roles and abilities. Facilitating the management and front and back end management of permissions. WebAPI REST interface, angular, and Twitter Bootstrap.
- RedRocket Framework: Custom n-tier framework built to ease development and testability
- Angular PIMS: Convert classic asp menu structure to modern ui implemented in angular, and REST using the security component to build menu structures.
- Jarvis: Code generation tool to ease development in angular built

NEXBUSINESS | CLEARFIELD, UT

Jan 2007 - Jan 2013 Owner

Responsibilities

- · Client and Project Management
- Architecting solutions for various projects ranging from simple to complex
- · Built and contributed open source frameworks
- · Sales and contracts

Notable Projects

- **Greenix Mobile Application** Built mobile web application to manage service agreements and clients while utilizing the infrastructure and technology constraints. Built with Rails, node is and angular.
- Launchpad User Management Built a oath2 permission based framework that was utilized by numerous clients built with angularjs and node.js
- **nSpeed** Built software to help the nuclear industry's vendors ensure compliance with various sub contractors and was built with Ruby on Rails
- Translatr Term translation as a service built with Rails and and angular
- · Beacon Logging and health service node is and angular

NEUMONT UNIVERSITY I SLC, UT

July 2010 - January 2012 Adjunct Professor

Responsibilities

- · Build and taught .net curriculum
- Taught beginning .net to advanced .net (console, asp.net, wcf services, wpf, threading, linq, expressions, etc)
- · Worked with students on project based learning

CRMCULTURE I BOULDER, CO

Jan 2010 - Jan 2011 Senior Software Engineer

Responsibilities

Managed service oriented architecture between Pivotal Platform and various clients

• Lead a team of 5 developers that spanned 5 different states

WAZI WEB I SLC, UT

Jul. 2008 - Jan. 2010 Senior Software Engineer

Responsibilities

- · Managed Team of 5-7 developers
- Worked on a variety of platforms (.net, and java)
- · Handled client relationships and sales, and product management
- Hired developers
- · Used and implemented agile methodologies
- · Implemented a test driven development.

Notable Projects

- Content Management System Conceptualized and built a content management system for various clients. The system was built on top of mvc.net and had the ability to build modules specific to the client. Was successfully deployed over 25+ times.
- Red Rhino Mail Mass newsletter emailing program. Red Rhino Mail gave business owners the ability to send template emails to their customers, and leads. The system sent out over 150,000 emails a day and was built on top of various technologies including (.net, java, mvc.net, etc)
- Business Social Networking Platform The platform was built around business needing to find new avenues and customers. Used both the content management system, and the red rhino mail.

REFERENCES

Available upon request